What if I told you there were brand new
construction duplexes here in Central
Texas with one side already rented out
for under $400,000?
Well, today we're touring three
completed duplexes here in Copperas Cove
with that one side already rented out
and then we're headed over to Temple,
Texas where Wellmore Homes is building
four new duplexes, [music]
that's eight units in total, in one of
Temple's growing communities.
>> [music]
>> So, whether you are an experienced
investor looking to expand your
portfolio, a newer investor looking for
a home hack, or maybe you're just a
first-time home buyer [music] looking to
rent out one side to lower that monthly
mortgage, this is a video you're not
going to want to miss.
>> [music]
>> Hey, and welcome to Living in Central
Texas. If you are new to the channel,
I'm Andrea Dudik, realtor, associate
broker, and your local relocation
specialist here in the Central Texas
area.
>> [music]
>> On this channel, we cover everything
from home tours, community tours, new
construction, and all things living and
vibe here in the Central Texas area.
Today's video is going to look a little
bit different [music] as we showcase one
of our building partners, Wellmore
Homes. Now, [music] Wellmore Homes
builds beautiful new construction and
semi-custom homes in the Central Texas
area, but they are also building these
really fabulous [music] investment
opportunity duplexes. Let's go take a
look.
Copperas Cove has been a popular market
for investors because of its proximity
to Fort Hood. With thousands of military
personnel, civilian employees,
contractors, [music]
and families moving in and out of the
area every year, rental demand remains
strong. [music]
Wellmore Homes currently has three
completed duplexes available here in
Heritage Place
>> [music]
>> with 106 Leon Street, 110 Leon Street,
and 114 Leon Street. Each duplex offers
two [music] separate units, and every
unit includes three bed, two bath, one
car garage, and approximately 1,253
[music] sq ft per side. This means
you're getting over 2,500 sq ft of
rentable [music] space per duplex.
So, each one of these duplexes are
totally different on the exterior,
[music] which is really fabulous. You
can see the one to the left has that
Tex-Mex stone, and then this one that
we're going to tour first [music]
has the limestone with that really
pretty black painted [music] siding, and
then the final one has a really pretty
reddish-gray
brick [music] mix with some uh stucco.
So, really beautiful just depending on
your vibe, [music]
and again, your B side is rented out on
all of these.
>> [music]
>> All three of these units are three bed,
two bath, over just over 1,200 sq
[music] ft.
This one has that really beautiful gray
wall,
or gray [music] paint color.
We have some black granite countertops,
[music]
great white cabinet space, uppers,
pretty green lowers, [music]
stainless steel appliances.
They didn't skimp [music] out on the
fixtures, which I think is wonderful.
Nice stainless steel oversized sink.
And even though these are under 1,300
[music] sq ft, they're super open
concept, so I think you could really do
great with
some furniture [music] in here. Blinds
are included.
Right off of there is a single car
garage.
>> [music]
>> You have
really fabulous
um
pantry space, [music] where is washer
dryer over here.
You have your vinyl [music] plank
flooring,
granite countertops,
fully tiled tub shower combo.
That's your secondary [music]
bathroom.
Great linen closet.
No carpet, [music]
so really low maintenance here.
You have
space for [music] your cabinet space or
closet space.
These standard
>> [music]
>> Honeywell
thermostats.
And then these
>> [music]
>> Each of these duplexes is going to
mirror one another.
Two of these duplexes have the vinyl
plank flooring, and then the final one
has some [music] stained concrete for a
totally different look.
So this primary bath has a single basin,
granite countertops,
walk-in shower,
and a
and a walk-in closet.
I'll pop you on out [music] to the
backyard.
Not much different from an [music]
apartment
is you actually have a decent-sized
backyard on these duplexes with the full
privacy fence.
And you do have that full
brick exterior. [music]
And there is irrigation.
So, no hand [music] watering.
Okay, our [music] second duplex is this
lighter Tex Mex color stone all the way
around.
Some warm and cool tones throughout.
[music]
And this one is the stained concrete,
and I'm actually kind of loving how this
one turned out.
But you have a white colored wall.
The gray [music] stained concrete.
And they did a taupe colored cabinet,
which I'm thinking is accessible beige.
But it looks beautiful. You still have
those stainless steel appliances.
Deep stainless steel sink.
I'll give you a peek inside the garage.
Nothing
crazy, but
good to take a look [music] at.
So, So a single car garage with
>> [music]
>> Sorry, electric
Oh my gosh, motorized garage with your
electrical panel out here
and [music] your water heater.
And this is the same floor plan. They're
all [music] the same floor plan. They
just look slightly different depending
on what your aesthetic is.
And your walk-in pantry [music]
and oh, it looks like I might need to
build that one out still.
That's your
back patio out there.
Your white granite countertops [music]
with that accessible beige or those
taupe color cabinets,
some gray [music] fully tiled
tub shower combo, linen closet.
Again, your [music] secondary bedrooms
that both have fans
and no carpet. [music] So once again,
super easy maintenance on these units.
Single vanity,
fully tiled walk-in shower,
and your walk-in [music] closet.
If you would like to see that third
unit, go ahead and give me a call. I'd
be happy to tour it for you, but we're
actually going to head on over to
Temple.
>> [music]
>> 106 Leon Lane is a little cutie with
side B already rented out. The exterior
is a mix of that white [music] Austin
limestone and an off-white stucco. I
love the cute covered front porch area
and fully sodded and fenced backyard.
[music] Throughout the home, you'll find
the luxury vinyl plank, some really cute
pendant lighting, two-tone cabinets,
stainless steel appliances, [music]
and the super functional and open
concept floor plan. [music]
There's a great use of storage in this
floor plan,
fans in all of the bedrooms,
>> [music]
>> and not having carpet really helps the
long-term durability of this home.
One thing I really like about Wal Mar
Homes is they don't build investment
properties that feel like investment
[music] properties.
When you walk in, you'll notice the open
concept floor plan, durable flooring,
[music] natural light, and modern
finishes throughout. The kitchen offers
plenty of cabinet [music] space, modern
appliances with a built-in microwave,
electric range, dishwasher, and a layout
that people are going to appreciate.
The primary bedroom has a spacious
bedroom, walk-in closet, and a
well-designed bathroom with a large
shower.
Outside, you'll find private fenced
backyards,
covered front porches, and one of
[music] my favorite features, the
four-sided masonry construction. All
three of these properties are wrapped in
stone, brick, [music] or a mix of stone,
brick, stucco, and hardie plank.
Currently, each duplex [music] already
has one side rented. For many investors,
that's a huge advantage because you're
purchasing a property with immediate
income already in place. And for those
of you that are interested in a housing
[music] hack, this could be an
incredible opportunity. Imagine living
in one side [music] while the tenant on
the other side helps offset your
mortgage payment. It's one of the
fastest ways many investors build wealth
[music] through real estate. But here's
the part that many people don't realize.
>> [music]
>> When you're buying a duplex and planning
to occupy one side, lenders will often
allow you to use a portion of the
anticipated rental income from the other
unit to help you qualify for the loan.
Typically, lenders can use up to 75%
[music] of the estimated market rent as
qualifying income. Now, one of the
biggest misconceptions I hear is people
thinking that they need a huge amount of
money to buy an investment property.
>> [music]
>> The reality is if you're purchasing a
duplex as your primary residence and
living in one side, there are some very
attractive financing options [music]
available.
For example, FHA financing can be as
little as 3.5%
[music] down, conventional financing can
be as little as 5% down, and VA [music]
financing for eligible veterans and
active duty military members can be 0%
down with again, [music] the intent to
purchase the duplex as your primary
residence and live in one side. It's one
of the reasons duplexes are often
considered one of the best entry points
[music] into real estate investing. Of
course, every lender and loan program is
a little different, so you'll want to
speak with a qualified loan officer
about your specific [music] situation.
If you're interested in financing one of
these duplexes,
>> [music]
>> I recommend contacting a local lender.
Jacob Studdard, one of my favorite local
lenders, is below. Whether you're
looking at FHA with 3 [music] and 1/2%
down, conventional as little as 5% down,
or VA financing with 0% down for
eligible borrowers, Jacob can help you
explore your options and determine what
[music] you qualify for.
Here with my friend and builder Glenn
Morrison with Welmar Homes. We met about
a year ago on a different home and we've
continued to work together ever since.
>> Yeah, Glenn Morrison. I'm co-owner of
Welmar Homes. Been in the business for
several years now having retired from
municipal government back in 2016.
[music]
Uh we take great pride in what we do,
especially with our custom clients. Uh
it's a real opportunity to get exactly
what you want and we want to take the
pressure off and just make the the
process so much easier that you can
relax and enjoy the build.
>> Okay, friends, we've arrived in Waters
Crossing here in Temple,
>> [music]
>> Texas. I was going to do this outside
and walk you around, but they've already
started framing, so it's just extra loud
and that was impossible.
But, we've arrived. I It's good to know
that actually Temple is one of the
fastest growing communities in Central
Texas because [music] of its healthcare
system, Baylor Scott & White, its
proximity to I-35, [music] and its
convenient location between Austin,
Waco, and Fort Hood. Willow Moor Homes
is building these four duplexes that is
eight rental unit, and they've already
picked out the floor plans, but we
haven't picked out the selections just
yet, so I'm super excited about that.
These will also be [music] three-bed,
two-bath units, actually larger than the
Copperas Cove units. These are going to
be 2,700-ish
square [music] feet in total, so what is
that? 13 and 1/2 per side. [music] So, a
little bit bigger. The price points will
still be under 400,000.
I'm really excited about it. Now, if you
have any questions [music] about these
duplexes, about investing in the Central
Texas area, or just relocating to
Central Texas in general, [music]
I'd love to be your vibe. You can find
all my contact information below. Don't
forget to like, subscribe, [music]
and click the bell notifications so that
you can stay up-to-date on all things
real estate here in Central Texas. Till
next time.